Mia Matos

Software Engineer & Technical Product Manager

Experienced Software Developer and Scrum Master with 5+ years of experience in software development, directing program management, and mitigating high complexity dependencies. Adept at facilitating Scrum rituals and conducting technical discussions. Improved project timelines and success metrics by 20% and 15% respectively, within 2 years.

Work Experience

Software Engineer

Zylo

Mar 2021 - Aug 2024

- » Applied technical knowledge to complete 8 technical discussions with cross-functional teams, leading to unblocking program outcomes, clearly defined scopes, and improving overall project productivity.
- » Harmonized project's technical direction with product and technical strategy, resulting in a 20% improvement in project timelines over two years.
- » Aligned stakeholders and escalated high complexity dependencies and risks, resulting in 15% improvement in project success metrics.
- » Created 3 dashboards and automation tools, resulting in 10% decrease in time spent on manual tasks and improved decision-making for technical programs
- » Created 5 new integrations by custom building internal connections utilizing external, 3rd-party APIs, resulting in a 30% increase in data accessibility to enable clients to make informed SaaS decisions.
- » Assisted in conducting interviews with prospective engineers via Zoom. Identified and recommended 5 skilled engineers, resulting in an increase in team productivity by filling gaps in expertise within 2 years.

Software Developer and Scrum Master

Octo Consulting

Jun 2019 - Mar 2021

» Modernized monolithic service from OSGi to SpringBoot to support containerization and improve maintainability. Phoenix, AZ martin.mia97@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/git-mmartin http://mcat97.github.io/

Skills

Engineering: JavaScript, Node.js, Python, React, Typescript

Product: Agile Processes, End to End Management, Research, Risk Management, Velocity Tracking

Tools: Aha!, AWS, Confluence, Docker, Git, Jira

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

University of Wisconsin -Parkside Kenosha, WI

Volunteering & Leadership

Zylo Inc

Mar 2023 - May 2024 DEI Co-Chair

Zylo Inc

Jan 2023 - Dec 2023 Women of Zylo Chair

- » Directed the communication of team's final program increment plan to program management and stakeholders, aligning government stakeholders and providing clarity in the management of budgets. Enhanced visibility and informed decision-making for successful program execution.
- » Managed high complexity dependencies and risks between teams, aligning stakeholders and escalating as needed, resulting in successful delivery of 100% of programs with major risks reported.
- » Facilitated Scrum rituals for development team, leading to 15% reduction in sprint planning time and enhanced transparency.